英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with Day 4 for the month of September.
Hi everyone, I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
今日木曜日は今週練習した表現を実際の会話で使えるようにトレーニングしてきます。
OK, let's get started.
Express.
Create.
Reply.
まずはウォーミングアップをしましょう。
Step 1. Express.
今からジェニーさんが今週練習した表現をランダムに言ってくれますので、
何も見ないで全部リピートできるかチャレンジしてみてください。
So, try to repeat each phrase after me.
And copy my intonation.
Okay, here we go.
It's cold for September.
We need warm clothes.
Did you bring a scarf today?
I'm looking for my jacket. It's dark green.
I get cold very easily.
All right! Did you express all those phrases quickly and smoothly?
And now, let's move on to the next step.
Step 2. Create.
続いては、今週練習したフレーズを使ってオリジナルの英文を作ってみましょう。
まずはこちら。
うちの制服は何々色です。
Our uniforms are 何々。
会社や学校の制服について、それが何色か説明する文を作りましょう。
いきますよ。
Our uniforms are...
どうぞ。
できましたか?
では、ジェニーさんならどんな文を作るか聞きましょう。
ジェニー。
Our uniforms are light blue with white stripes.
ライトブルーで止めないで。
With white stripes.
That's a good one.
さあ、それでは同じフレーズ、Our uniforms are...を使ってもう一度文を作りましょう。
先ほどとは違う文を作ってみてくださいね。
いきましょう。
Our uniforms are...どうぞ。
Very good!
二つ目の文です。
今日は何々を着ます。
I'm going to wear 〇〇 today.
今日どんな服を着たいか伝える文を作りましょう。
アクセサリーや帽子についてでもいいですよ。
I'm going to wear 〇〇 today.
Okay, now it's Jenny's turn.
I'm going to wear this scarf today.
That's a good one.
それではもう一度文を作ってみましょう。
I'm gonna wear...
どうぞ。
では三つ目です。
パーティーなどイベントでのシーン。
おじいはあそこにいます。
なになにを着ています。
My uncle is over there.
He's wearing...
なになに。
一目で分かるようにどんな服を着ているか説明しましょう。
帽子やネクタイなどでもOKですよ。
余裕があったらそれが何色なのかも言ってみましょう。
ではこの2文を言ってみよう。
Ready?
My uncle is over there. He's wearing...
どうぞ。
OK.
All right, Jenny, it's your turn.
My uncle is over there.
He's wearing a dark green shirt.
Koi midori no shatsu.
A dark green shirt.
Soredeba, mou ichito bun wo tsukutte mimashou.
My uncle is over there.
He's wearing nani nani.
Dozo.
All right, nice job.
Now let's move on to our final step.
Step 3, reply.
さて、ここからはさらに実践的なトレーニングをします。
英語の問いかけに英語で自由に返答しましょう。
まず一つ目、想像してください。
僕とあなたはスコットランドの湖を訪れています。
そこで僕が、
It's a beautiful lake, isn't it?
Beautiful lake, isn't it?
We'll call it.
Imagine the scene and answer freely.
You can say about the weather.
Here we go.
Beautiful lake, isn't it?
Go ahead.
Let's listen to the answer.
Beautiful lake, isn't it?
Yeah, the autumn leaves are so colorful now.
〜isn't it?と言われたら、
Yeah, plus 〜これが基本ですね。
今は紅葉がとても色鮮やかですね。
The autumn leaves are so colorful now.
それではみなさん、もう一度トライしましょう。
同じ問いかけをしますよ。
Beautiful lake, isn't it?
どうぞ。
それでは2つ目のクエスチョンに行きましょう 9月の日本は寒いか聞きます Is Japan cold in September? 日本の気候について説明しましょう 行きます Is Japan cold in September? どうぞ
では、返答例です。
Is Japan cold in September?
Not really. It's getting cold, but usually we have nice, warm, sunny fall weather.
それではみなさん、もう一度トライしましょう。
Is Japan cold in September?
では、最後のクエスチョンです。
あなたは寒がりかどうか聞きます。
Do you get cold easily?
自分なりに答えましょう。
いきますよ。
Do you get cold easily?
どうぞ。
では、返答例を聞きましょう。
Do you get cold easily?
Yes, I do. I get cold very easily.
I'm always cold, so I always wear layers.
Do you get cold easily?
Yes, I do.
However, the original use of this yes, I do in conversation is an important role.
Jenny-san no hento rei de wa, do you get cold easily? ni taishite, yes, I do. Hai, masashiku.
Kono you na iikata mo ok desu ne.
Soshite sono ato, hieishou ni tsuite no bun mo itte kuremashita. I'm always cold.
Sorede wa, mou ichi to onaji toikake wo shimasu.
Mae yori mou skoshi shikari kotaete mimashou.
Do you get cold easily?
Okay, time's up.
All right, great job today, everyone.
Create, express, reply.
And now you're ready for a conversation.
ということで、明日金曜日は
カンバーセーションパートナーの
ノラさんとスコットランドの
美しい湖へと出かけますよ。
今週練習した表現を
会話でぜひ使ってみてくださいね。
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.